[Laughter]
when you was sent to the Council of
ducks you become a twitch
streamer so one way to find Focus that
that I forgot to talk about is something
called the rubber duck method and I want
to talk about this for a second it's
actually really fun the idea I mean
every time I think about the rubber duck
method I can't help I mean I'm from you
know I'm Gen X right so I I I hear
Burton Ernie's you know rubber ducky y
for the
one you make B time so much fun what
does this have to do with
technology um I would I mean I really
need a rubber duck right now to to make
the point so imagine a rubber duck in my
hand right
here so what does it mean to rubber duck
and what the hell does this have to do
with um preparing mentally for Tech work
um the truth is that the idea of rubber
ducking is you hold up a rubber duck or
it could be a doggy or your favorite you
know mythical god from Norse or Hindu
mythology who doesn't matter um and you
talk to them you just talk to them you
just you tell you talk through your
problem to your rubber ducky he like
well I could do
blah and for some reason the focus on
another entity as oppos to just talking
to I don't know God or Mother Earth or
something it makes it more real and I'm
not going to lie why one of the things
that has made this really successful for
me and I encourage you to explore this
as well is is streaming to Twitch um I I
I I can think of a number of of live
streamers now who um one one in
particular who started streaming because
you know I met them and they they came
in and I said no we we need more
beginners to rubber duck their learning
they need to talk through what it is
that they're learning and how they're
learning it because there's other people
who want to participate so one of the
cool things about live streaming in 2024
and we know the fact that we live in the
future is that we can actually have a
community you know a small or a large
community be our rubber ducks they can
sit there and they can listen and they
can say and so you can sit there and
talk through a problem like wondering
whether it be you know how to hack a
particular thing on track me or hack the
box or how to you know set up a get of
action right or or you know and and you
don't have any idea how to do it but
you're like talking through it maybe
it's an algorithm that you need to like
um to figure out and you know the twitch
software and and and game development
category as well as the Science and
Technology category are replete with
examples of twitch streamers who are
using their live stream as their rubber
duck and so it's really great because
the rubber duck talks
back sometimes the rubber duck back back
back seats right and tells you what to
do it's like uh no you're doing it wrong
sometimes the rubber duct totally trolls
you and calls you an idiot I mean that's
twitch you just got to be ready to do
that but the technique is very simple
you just talk through the problem with
an imaginary rubber duck as if you're
explaining what you're doing and I can
attest to this if you do this you will
find Solutions in fact I am this is so
hard for me to admit I am the old guy
who goes for a walk live stream or not
who's out for a walk in nature and I am
talking to myself and I know that there
have been people who have looked at me
like yet another old guy is talking to
himself but a lot of time you would not
believe I I like will take a piece of
paper like paper you know sometimes I'll
use my phone but most of the time it's
paper I'll take paper and pen with me
and I'll go for a walk and I'm like
trying to think through a problem or a
solution or a better architectural way
of doing something or a life decision
what it is I want to be in life and I'll
be walking and I'll be talking to myself
sometimes I pretend like there's another
person there sometimes I mean you might
want to pray to God however you want to
do it but you're like talking and
sometimes yeah I hear things
back I don't know does that mean I'm
crazy I am crazy I mean let's just be
real I am but but the point of it is is
that the process of talking through the
thing actually scientifically
neurologically is is sound it's a way of
you to find a solution to whatever
you're trying to figure out and you will
end up tangentially identifying other
ideas that you would not have found had
you not vocalized the issue at hand so
talking to the duck talk to the hand
talk to the duck talk to the live stream
talk to God talk to Mother Nature talk
to saan for all I care you're going to
figure it out that's how you'll do it by
the way your live streaming
saan probably the same thing